In this lecture, we're going to look at the second lever for inference optimization,
which is cross region inferencing. And this is really important. Cross region inference uses
inference profiles to increase throughput and improve resilience by routing requests across
multiple AWS regions during peak utilization burst. So at certain times,
there could be some scenarios where there is not enough capacity within a particular region
to service your request by the Amazon bedrock service. So in those scenarios, you can use cross
region inference and your request would be routed to a different AWS region. So let's say you
center request either through console SDK or API. This request will go to Amazon bedrock service
and let's say you only want to use us east one. So your request will be sent to us east one,
but if there is scenario where there is not enough capacity, you will experience
throttling. Now, if you enable cross region inference, then Amazon bedrock is going to route
that request to a different region, let's say us east two or some other region where there is
sufficient capacity to service your request. So how does the model know that whether this needs
to be routed to a single AWS region or you can do cross region inference. And that is through
by defining the inference profile for your model. So let's take a look. So here you can see
I have written this border three code to send an API request to Amazon bedrock, but here if you
see the model ID, I have defined this as entropic dot cloud three haiku. When you want to use a
global inference profile, then you start with global and then model ID. Now, as we discussed when
we use global here, that means it can be routed to any AWS region across the globe, but now
there could be some scenarios like in Europe, you have the GDPR regulation. So you might not want
your data to go outside the European Union. In that case, AWS has something known as geographic
cross region. Now, let's say your primary region is in US. So what you can do is you can define
us dot the name of the model. So it's going to then only route to you can see here either Canada
see a West US East US West. So only in AWS regions within US and Canada. Similarly, if you are
in Europe, so then you can define with this EU. So if you define global, that means it can be routed
to any region across the globe. But if you define the geographical region and then the model ID,
it will be routed only within that geographic region. Now, a quick difference between geographic
cross region inference and global cross region inference. So if you have some data residency
requirements, then you can use this geographic cross region inference within US, UN,
attack. But if you don't have any data residency requirement, you can use any AWS
commercial region worldwide. So from the throughput perspective, AWS says geographic cross
region inference, it is higher than the single region. And for global cross region inference,
it's the highest. So choose global for maximum performance. Then from the cost perspective,
it's standard pricing. If you use global cross region inference, it's going to be 10% saving.
So choose global for cost optimization. And then in terms of the SCP requirement,
so if you have service control policies within your organization, so you can define your service
control policy and allow all destination regions in profile. And if you're using global cross
region inference, then you can set AWS requested region to unspecified. So finally, AWS says
for geographic cross region inference, if your organization has data residency regulations,
then choose this one. So if you don't have any data residency requirements,
and you are prioritizing for cost and performance, then go for global cross region inference.
Now, let's take a look at the third inference optimization approach. And that is latency optimization
strategies. So AWS says latency optimized inference for foundation models in Amazon bedrock,
delivers faster response times and improved responsiveness for AI applications. So how do you do
that? So AWS says there are some models which are very suited for low latency use cases balancing
speed and quality. So those are Amazon Nova Pro. Then you have from entropic cloud 3.5
high co model and meta llamas 3.1 4, 0, 5 billion and 70 billion models. So these three models
are optimized for low latency. Finally, there is one more way in which you can optimize your
latency. That is by setting the latency parameter to optimized while calling the Amazon
bedrock runtime API. So here if you see I have pasted some go to three code where we are making
an API request to the Amazon bedrock. So there is a configuration parameter called as performance
config latency. And it has two options standard and optimize. So this is an optional
configuration parameter. So if you don't provide any value, then it will take standard. But if you
want to optimize your latency, then you provide this optimized value. Okay, so that is pretty much
it from this lecture. I will see in the next lecture.